Theme Tune: [music playing]
Al: Hello Farmers! And welcome to another episode of the Harvest Season. My name is Al,
Kevin: My name is Kevin.
Al: and we're here today to talk about Cottagecore Games.
Al: This episode, yes, we are talking about Pokopia again. It's time for another Pokopia episode!
Kevin: People we didn't have enough. I don't think we need to correct that
Al: More more more more we need to see whether whether
Al: we've overtaken animal crossing new horizons with the number of episodes on or not
Kevin: Oh, I mean inevitably we will yeah, you know, you know what i'm so excited for how this is going to be dropping
Al: because I think that was the previous record holder
Kevin: Let's see, what is the date, uh, yeah, no the the
Kevin: Is going to be dropping right before or maybe the day of the next dlc is being announced. No day after but uh
Al: Oh okay yes of course because the direct is on the it'll be after yeah because um it's uh it's
Kevin: Yeah the day after yeah
Al: three no the same day because it's the ninth is the the the nintendo direct no the eighth is
Kevin: Elbow oh, I thought it was the 9th and 10th. It's the 8th and 9th. Okay. Oh
Al: zelda i'm pretty sure this is it i'm pretty sure it's the eighth and uh for the zelda one let me
Al: check let me pull up that handy dandy nintendo today app and open up the calendar
Kevin: Nah, I mean, I need to get that.
Al: it is actually useful it actually is useful the eighth
Kevin: I hear it's good.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: That's going to be a good time.
Al: is the zelda direct and the ninth is the nintendo direct oh yeah
Kevin: Double much.
Kevin: It's really funny state of play.
Kevin: Also did two technically, but they were both not very good.
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: And then Nintendy, just dropping there.
Kevin: But yeah, going back to the point, yeah, it's great, as in true Harvest Season fashion,
Kevin: this will be outdated upon release. Or we'll be behind.
Al: Yeah, all right. So yeah, we're going to talk about Pocopia Bubbly Basin this episode, the
Al: first part of the DLC. Obviously there's free update to talk about as well, so we will talk
Al: about both of those things in this episode. Before that, we have some news. But first
Al: of all, Kevin, what have you been up to, Mr Traveller?
Kevin: Uh, yeah, in the rare occurrence, I have gone ventured off into the world.
Kevin: I have been not for work.
Kevin: Um, I've been, uh, I went to San Francisco about a week ago from recording.
Kevin: Uh, and the reason for that, uh, Pokemon worlds and XP were held there.
Kevin: You see, and I happened to attend.
Kevin: Um, yeah, that is correct.
Al: And you're Georgia normally, right? That's where you live?
Al: Yeah.
Kevin: Yes.
Kevin: So that is across the country.
Al: So that's quite a distance then.
Kevin: It is, it is a, a venture and a half, unfortunately I only had the one day
Kevin: pass, so I couldn't enjoy the full experience, but, um, yeah, it was, I
Kevin: mean, obviously I enjoyed it overall, you know, got to see some good, actually.
Kevin: Everyone I saw has been on the show.
Kevin: I saw Greg, I saw Aislinn and Spencer.
Al: Ah nice
Kevin: Um, yeah.
Kevin: Um, so everyone's been on the show.
Kevin: while them good times were had. The...
Kevin: the event itself, I don't know, I'm torn.
Kevin: On the one hand, like, it's very nicely decorated.
Kevin: They made a big, you know,
Kevin: big show of the Pokemon's in San Francisco.
Kevin: They probably share some photos on the Slack,
Kevin: I probably will.
Kevin: Oh, a bunch of photos I haven't shared.
Kevin: Like the, they had a, basically a bridge,
Kevin: the Golden Gate Bridge arc sort of thing
Kevin: with the incentive.
Kevin: There's a lot of people who are going to be interested in this.
Kevin: how many people are going, right? They sell a limited amount of tickets.
Kevin: But lines everywhere for the event. So, okay, you know, let me back up a second.
Kevin: First of all, this is the first year they split up the actual Worlds competition
Kevin: and what they call Pokemon XP, a sort of side convention. Exactly. Ah, there you go.
Al: Yeah, experience.
Kevin: And the, what it felt like was, let's make this sort of Pokemon Pong sort of thing,
Kevin: or at least that's how I took it originally. Because, you know, originally Worlds was just
Kevin: competition, but they've been growing and showing, you know, as more people attended.
Kevin: And I do think it was a smart idea to have a separate event for people who don't compete.
Kevin: But I think they struggled a little. First off, it's very weird limiting so many of the
Kevin: panels and workshops and events. And like, incredibly limited. You know, there are thousands
Kevin: one had maybe a hundred. I know they have capacities or whatever, but they only ran it
Kevin: once or twice a weekend or whatever. So, yeah, just so mind boggling. There were so many events
Kevin: that so many people couldn't attend to. The stuff that you could go as, you know, just a person in
Kevin: the event, there were some booths that were for buying things, you know, like Bandai Namco,
Kevin: Build-A-Bear had a thing lego had stuff going on um
Kevin: a lot of photo opportunities they can you know take a picture with blastos and charizard take
Kevin: a picture with um the lego blastos charizard venusaur take a picture with nidorina nidorino
Kevin: and gecko you know all the highlights um take a picture with the little mascots that come out
Kevin: um but all that stuff had lines and pretty significant lines um I would say the average
Kevin: line was at least an hour.
Kevin: a few basically art exhibits I'd call it, they were showing off some of the TCG artwork and the original paintings or drawings, they had some of Yukimori's clay figures out on display which was nice, they had what they called the little museum, a collection of all the consoles and boxes basically throughout the history, and a number of merchandise items which was nice, but yeah just a walkthrough of a little museum experience.
Kevin: Probably one of their best things, they had a lot of music going on because there was an outdoor portion of the venue and they had a lot of great musicians, they had one of the guys who I think the main composer, what was his name, his name is Carlos, his username is InsaneInTheRain, he's one of the composers for ZA.
Al: Okay.
Kevin: Yeah, and so he did a live performance.
Kevin: days and I got to see one of them doing ZA music live in person, it was great. Of course they had
Kevin: Lady Jacinthe's theme. He did the shopping theme actually, which you don't think about, but it's
Kevin: really good actually. They had a number of other musical performances, so those were all pretty
Kevin: solid. They had some of the people who sang some of the themes for the English versions.
Kevin: Brought by and they performed that as well. So music was good. They had a lot of the
Kevin: little Pokemon mascots running around, you know, people in the suits. I'm assuming they're all
Kevin: Japanese women because they're all really, really short to be honest. Yeah, I got a picture with
Kevin: Lapras, that's the only one I saw. They had a little like Pokemon parade, you know, just
Al: Did lapras have legs?
Kevin: The lapras had, uh, I mean, it had flippers.
Kevin: Um, I assumed there are leg holes at the bottom that you couldn't see, um, because, you know,
Al: How did lapras walk around?
Kevin: it's just on its body.
Kevin: So I'm sure the feet were like popping out of the chest.
Al: Okay, horrifying.
Kevin: Um, uh, you couldn't see it.
Kevin: It worked well.
Kevin: The illusion was maintained.
Kevin: Um, the funny, yeah, lapras, yeah, all the mascots would walk around and move around
Al: Could you see lapras moving around?
Kevin: and whatnot.
Kevin: Um, yeah, I'm honestly, lapras was probably impressive because I think they had mechanisms
Kevin: to make like the head and
Kevin: the feet. I don't know how it worked but it was impressive. The one really funny one
Kevin: is Geodude because they just had a person in a suit and you could see the legs just
Kevin: straight out popping out. I have to ask Aislinn, she had a picture of Geodude performer.
Kevin: But yeah, plenty of mascots, plenty of pictures out and about dancing. A few dancing shows.
Kevin: Yeah, but that was that was good stuff the
Kevin: But I think what other events of course they had a huge
Kevin: sections dedicated to game demos, but
Kevin: Someone who's you know huge Pokemon fan. I didn't go to that because I found all those games
Al: Yeah, demos for everything's out already. There's nothing other than Winds and Waves, which they're not gonna have a demo for yet
Kevin: Exactly right which is weird
Kevin: Yeah, which is kind of weird
Kevin: Because the last time I went to worlds in Nashville
Kevin: Let's go was coming out so they had a demo for let's go which was cool because of the game wasn't out
Kevin: Yeah, it's very weird. They dedicated so much space to
Kevin: game area, but they didn't
Al: Yeah, I think they had that when I was in London Worlds as well. I think that was one
Kevin: have
Kevin: Yeah
Al: of the years there wasn't a game coming out. And then, oh wait, no, looking at this, Scarlet
Al: and Violet was coming out but they didn't have demos of that. So they had demos of Legends
Al: Arceus which was already out. And again, yeah, that was months and months and months ago.
Kevin: Oh, that's really weird.
Al: It was like six months by that point. But I don't know why they didn't have Scarlet
Kevin: Yeah, that's weird that that frame.
Al: and Violet demos. I just remember, yeah, because it was 2022, I remember being there and being
Al: like oh that's weird, nothing new here. And I guess at the time it would have been weird
Kevin: well I could yeah I could tell you why because it wasn't working at that point a bit
Al: that there was no Scarlet and Violet. I've just forgotten about that.
Al: Well, yeah, it depends who you believe.
Kevin: I know i'm kidding but uh yeah yeah well but i'm just saying just based off what came out but
Kevin: um but um but yeah they had that um well they had this one fun little event they call it a voiceover
Kevin: booth, as we all know. I like making silly voices.
Kevin: And it was actually probably the shortest line. It was like 10 minutes.
Kevin: It was just this like arcade cabinet with a microphone sticking out and it play you
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: a clip of the anime and basically kind of like karaoke track style.
Kevin: All right, you go and we'll play you the dialogue at the timer and you're recording your voice.
Al: Oh that's it, that's fun.
Kevin: Yeah, I was pretty impressed with my performance. I have a feeling they might have had something to
Kevin: to smooth out the audio a little because it can.
Kevin: It came out really good and suspiciously good.
Al: So it's not just that you could be good at it, no? Is that, that's not, that's not a
Kevin: Um...
Kevin: [laughs]
Al: possibility at all here, no?
Kevin: Uh... I... I don't know.
Al: Kevin, Kevin, look, I know, I know that it's hard to be positive about yourself, but that
Kevin: I don't trust myself that much.
Al: is a thing that we're allowed to do when we are good at things.
Kevin: Yeah I guess all right look I'll tell you what I have the recordings I took videos.
Al: Yeah.
Kevin: So I'll share it on the slack and people can judge.
Al: Greenhouse episode.
Kevin: But it was a fun idea there were only like it was pretty limited they were like oh they did
Kevin: have you could do it with another person because you know a lot of these scenes had two characters
Kevin: talking to each other so you could have someone else and kind of share the roles that was pretty
Kevin: It's pretty fun.
Al: frame.
Kevin: people with two voices, so I did not think about that.
Kevin: Anyways, I had the chance, but yeah, it was all from Horizons, so I don't know these characters
Kevin: that well, but it was very fun.
Al: I would have no idea, not because I don't watch the anime just now, I am watching, I'm
Al: watching every single episode, I'm just watching it in Japanese.
Kevin: That's really funny
Al: And not because I care about watching it in Japanese, many people will know if you listen
Kevin: Yeah
Al: to the podcast, I do not care about necessarily watching it in the original, it's just that
Al: they take so long to come out in English.
Kevin: Oh, yeah, no, that's fair
Kevin: I just don't know who they like I knew most of the characters at least from the promotion
Kevin: But I didn't there was some green-haired
Kevin: Rival caveman looking kid. I don't hold to something like that. I remember
Al: Oh yeah um oh um why have I forgotten his name uh oh that's really annoying that I can't remember
Al: his name I know I know who you mean um he's got he's got uh he's got a sableye that's his main
Kevin: Yeah. Yeah, I just I didn't I didn't know that character existed.
Al: pokemon um oh what's his name alt
Kevin: Oh, is it? Okay, cool. Yeah, I think I saw that in some of the promotion.
Kevin: Oh, yeah, that's it is awesome. I get older. That's the beauty brand. No, that's right. Yeah.
Kevin: That's correct. Um, yeah, that was fun. I voiced old and I voiced What is it? Roy,
Kevin: the main kid with Fuecoco? Yeah. Yeah. But they also had one you could do with Liko,
Al: Yeah, yeah, right
Kevin: you know, they had like a...
Kevin: Whatever her name is, the girls.
Kevin: Yeah, they had...
Kevin: That was a fun little thing where you could, you know, choose a scenario.
Kevin: They also had just straight up the intros, you could just straight up karaoke.
Kevin: I did not do that. Not that I wasn't opposed. I didn't think about it. Just, you know me.
Kevin: I tend to lean towards the voiceovers.
Al: yeah yeah. Do you know, just speaking of the anime, I remember when they were first teasing
Kevin: But...
Al: the new anime and they were like "oh, these are the two main characters, it's Riko and
Al: Roy" and everyone was like "oh, that must be a mistranslation, it's obviously going
Al: to be Riko and Roy" because it's like Riko is definitely the name that it's going to
Al: be and it's just a weird translation error. And now I'm thinking back and I'm like "Riko
Al: just sounds like the most normal name now.
Al: *laughs* No, it's really not. And it's not like Rico is somehow like completely normal, while Lico is completely weird. It's like, what are you doing?
Kevin: And Lika is not that bad
Kevin: Well, I mean Rico Rico is a common name but the kickers that's you generally a guy's name
Al: Yeah, it's certainly not a name I come across. So... *laughs* Like...
Kevin: Yeah, well, I mean on Scotland but maybe that's why but that would be weird cuz like clearly the guy was gonna be Roy
Kevin: So, I don't know and we have Lilo. So, you know, we're not going anyways, but um, I
Kevin: That is really funny that people it's gonna be real
Al: Just so funny.
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: But anyway, so yeah a lot of just wandering around and waiting in line so many lines
Kevin: Which again like very weird like I feel like they didn't know they were gonna have that capacity when they sold that many
Al: - Nice.
Al: Yeah, I wonder, so it's a couple of things.
Al: I wonder whether part of the problem
Al: is that you know how many people are gonna be there,
Al: but you don't know what they're gonna want to do
Al: at any one point, right?
Al: And also, like, do you just put more things on
Al: or do you let less people in, right?
Al: Because it's not really like you can just, like,
Al: triple the number of people in Pokemon Go.
Al: right like that's not going to reduce the demand on people wanting to have photos taken with them
Al: right like that that's not realistic um i'm i'm trying to think back to when when I went to world
Kevin: Yeah. Yeah.
Al: in london and because that was I think that one was the first one where they started doing the
Al: other the other stuff around it um and so like there was a um there was an outdoor place where
Al: where they were showing film.
Al: films and stuff like that. There was the obviously there was the shop, but they did
Al: that previous years and that just infinitely has that problem. And they had this area that
Al: had like a bunch of activities and stuff like that. And the way that they did it then, both
Al: for the shop and for the area with the activities, is you there were specific times where you
Al: could turn up and get a ticket for a specific time and then you would
Al: come back at that time and you'd get into this more controlled area where you could then do
Kevin: Mm-hmm
Al: the activities within that area and there were basically no queues inside the area.
Al: So I wonder why they didn't do that because that seemed to work quite well. Like I don't
Al: remember standing in queues for much at all and even the shop like yeah it was busy but
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: like we went at our assigned time we queued for five minutes and then we got in the shop and we
Al: bought stuff, right? Like, they actually...
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: did their queuing pretty well. Insert joke about it being in London and that's the one
Kevin: There you go.
Kevin: I wouldn't be surprised.
Al: where the queuing was good. But yeah, it's interesting. I wonder whether they just wanted
Al: it to be less restrictive because the restriction was getting into the area this time, right?
Al: You had to have a ticket to get into Pokemon XP, right? Whereas when it was in London,
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Al: The only place you needed to ticket was to get into the actual...
Al: ...room where the matches were happening.
Al: The rest of the conference centre and the area outside the conference centre, that was all completely open to the public.
Kevin: That's, that's wild, yeah, 'cause, yeah, 'cause, uh...
Al: And so maybe because they had the restriction of "you have to have a ticket to get into this area",
Al: then they were just a bit more lax on it and like, "well, it's not going to be a problem this time because we're limiting how many people there are".
Al: And you're like, yeah, but it's too many people for what you've got.
Al: got in the area, and they just kind of mucked that up.
Kevin: Yeah, what I'm not 100% sure either. Um, but the, the worst instance is 100% and the same because there's also kind of a highlight of the area. Um, the Pokemon Center.
Kevin: Um, yeah, of course, because so the.
Al: Of course
Al: Like that's just that's just that's the whole thing cuz you didn't go till Sunday, right? Yeah, so there would be nothing left
Kevin: That's correct.
Kevin: Yeah, okay. So the album starts with, so you need to...
Kevin: a separate ticket and reservation for the Pokemon Center. Separate from everything else.
Al: OK, so they still had it for that.
Al: OK, that's that's something, I guess.
Kevin: Yeah. Of course, when tickets were announced and they went live, it was a nightmare. The website
Kevin: couldn't handle the traffic. I was trying for an hour to get a reservation and didn't get one until
Kevin: Sunday at 3.15 p.m. I was trying for Saturday at 3 p.m. and had to keep sliding back because it just
Kevin: wasn't working. And of course, yeah, stuff was still not selling out. They said they were going
Kevin: to try to maintain some stock for each day. And...
Al: Yeah, their stock management is terrible. When we had it, it was like their limiting
Al: stock was you can buy six of the Pikachu plushies. I'm like, that's not limiting. Who needs six
Al: of them?
Kevin: Yeah, but here's the crazy thing. This time they limited one for every exclusive item.
Al: Yeah, because they're limiting you one per each item, so then everybody buys one of each
Kevin: So, okay, they limited it, but they still ran out. And it's wild because they had so much stock.
Al: item. It's like, if they actually want to limit it, they need to limit it to like a
Al: certain number of items full stop. Not just like, "You can buy one of everything!"
Al: Because then that's what they do. People go in, they buy one of everything!
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, I know. But like, it's just, it was, it was really awesome. It was brutal.
Kevin: The space was big. First of all, it was nicely done. It was coded. But um, I, I got a lot
Kevin: of stuff, not everything. And it's crazy because they basically had three, um, three angles
Kevin: or three different themes going on. They had the world championship theme with a little
Kevin: peek through the crown.
Kevin: Everything was orange and reddish, and they, uh, they, uh, and, and, yeah, and, and, and
Kevin: everything said world championships.
Kevin: They had Pokemon XP theme, which was the blue theme with the little astronaut Pikachu.
Al: Yeah, I think it's officially it's officially it's Pikachu and a Cosmog inspired
Kevin: And then they had San Francisco.
Al: Costume is what they called it
Kevin: Yeah, that's correct. Yeah, yeah, which is very cute.
Al: Gotta get the naming right come on Kevin brand awareness
Kevin: Oh, don't never recognize me.
Kevin: Um, anyways, so there was a boatload of stuff to get. Um, I got a good amount of stuff I got a decent haul. Um, they had Charizard with a little rocket jetpack as a plush, very happy with that one.
Kevin: Um, they had. Yeah, but I'm like the San Francisco stuff.
Kevin: I didn't get any of it. Um, but yeah.
Al: Yeah, yeah. I'm not surprised. The moment you said Sunday, I was like, yeah, you, yeah,
Kevin: Yeah, that's correct.
Al: no. Because when it was Worlds in London, I went on the Friday and I only just managed
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: to get some of the stuff. Some of the stuff was already sold out. There was stuff that
Al: I wanted and I couldn't get on the Friday. Friday! Madness! Thankfully, I did manage
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Yeah, that's correct. That's correct.
Al: to get the London Pikachu plushie. So I did get that, but yeah, there was so much.
Al: It's out of stock immediately, basically. Because they let in all the influencers, which
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: They
Kevin: Influencers
Kevin: Yeah
Al: is so stupid. Because the point of having influencers is to influence people in buying.
Al: But the thing is, the influencers buy it all. They're not influencing. They're just making
Kevin: Yeah, yeah
Al: people want stuff they can't get anymore. Hey, Pokemon, Pokemon, you don't need influencers.
Al: You've already got enough influence. You're done. You can't do any more influence. You
Kevin: You're in
Al: We're the biggest brand on the planet.
Kevin: The plot maybe second best influence in the world is Pikachu you just slap a Pikachu that's it
Al: Yeah, it's madness, like, oh, we need people to want our stuff.
Al: They want your stuff.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, I I don't even need to look at what the Pokemon plot
Kevin: Pikachu plush looks like I'm
Al: Exactly. I think part of the problem is that I don't think Pokemon fundamentally care.
Al: Because the fact is, they take a bunch of stuff, they sell it all, they get the money.
Al: Do they care who buys it? Not really. Obviously there will be some people in Pokemon who do.
Kevin: Yeah
Al: They want that. But like overall, the company do not care because they sell everything that
Kevin: Yeah, they're they're making their huge payday absolutely, um
Al: they want to. Done.
Kevin: but
Kevin: Yeah, I'm posting pictures on the slack right now for people. Oh anyway, so that was Pokemon Center is what it is
Kevin: um, they I forgot they had the
Kevin: Honda and Toyota the Miraidon and Koraidon
Kevin: Which was pretty cool. You couldn't touch them, but they were there glowing
Kevin: Well, Corridon actually booed.
Kevin: I didn't see it, but that was pretty cool.
Kevin: Um, they, um, and rare, rare pictures of actually of me, um, in this, um, there's me with a lapis right there.
Kevin: They had a Pikachu car. I don't know what kind of car it was, but it just looks like Pikachu.
Al: It's a Pikachu car, obviously.
Kevin: They had a fun little, you know, um, they had a trolley that looks like Rayquaza.
Kevin: That was very cool. Um, and all sorts of other nonsense. Um.
Kevin: There were a few other ones. There was, uh, inside the little museum, they had a wall with every Pokemon on a card, um, which was fun.
Kevin: They had all the Megas and G-Maxes too, so it was, you know, a couple walls worth of cards.
Kevin: Um, yeah, very, very, uh, nifty.
Kevin: Um, but, uh, but yeah, that was Worldsome.
Al: Oh, I see the, I see Lapras's feet, right at the front of the picture there.
Kevin: Oh, you see, you see the feet?
Al: I can just see them just poking out the front there.
Kevin: Yeah, um, well, I.
Al: You look so happy, Kevin.
Kevin: I made an effort to do big goofy smiles for all the pictures.
Kevin: Go over the top.
Al: That's how I do every photo, because if you don't do a big goofy,
Al: then then you might look stupid.
Kevin: Yeah, exactly. You have to go.
Al: At least if you look goofy, everyone knows you're trying to look goofy.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, exactly. You go go over the tops. Um, oh, you know what was cool and you know that book Pokemon ecology.
Kevin: You don't know that book. It's a book. It's it's officially licensed. It was
Kevin: would what did the ecology of the world look like in Pokemon?
Al: An illustrated guide to Pokemon Ecology.
Kevin: Yeah. Um, they, uh, they built, um, they built a few dioramas based off, um, based off those,
Kevin: uh, those pages in the book. So they were just nice little neat dioramas. I liked them,
Kevin: but they were just small little again, kind of in the art area. Um, uh, which obviously not as
Al: Yeah. Oh, that is a very large Pikachu.
Kevin: popular. It's very, that was a very big Pikachu. Um, yeah.
Al: Oh, that is, those are, those are fun dioramas.
Kevin: Yeah. The dioramas were really well done. I don't know why I talked to baseline. I,
Al: I like those.
Kevin: it might be like a Japanese culture thing that they're very big on photo opportunities because
Kevin: they invested a lot in their phone opportunities. Yeah, sure. Yeah. No, that that's probably a good
Al: I think we need to get a more detailed Greenhouse episode with the two of you on your world's experiences.
Kevin: one. Um, Oh yeah. Yeah. Um, yeah.
Al: Other than me just going like, "Yeah, sounds great, sounds great."
Kevin: Oh, another fun one. They had the smear, smear gold blockboard wall where you could just, uh,
Kevin: everyone could just, you know, draw whatever on. Um, and it's funny because by the end of the day,
Kevin: it was just, children just had scribbled over everything, you know, let me share my Pikachu
Al: [laughter]
Kevin: that I drew. I'll find it. But, um, anyway, so yeah, world's a lot of stuff. Yeah. Well,
Kevin: let's do a green. I'll do try to get aced or even Greg to do a greenhouse. I'm going to chat about,
Al: Oh yeah, yeah. Do something anyway.
Kevin: She did multi-day, so she has more she can talk about.
Kevin: Watching the championships was fun there, yada.
Kevin: Oh, they had pinball. I forgot about pinball.
Kevin: Anyways, yeah, worlds.
Kevin: Okay, enough worlds talk.
Kevin: Like I said, yeah, definitely worth a greenhouse.
Kevin: Yeah, other than that, mostly Pokopia.
Kevin: Obviously, I've been playing Bubbly based on the whole time.
Kevin: It actually invigorated me to play more of the actual Pokedex,
Kevin: which I hadn't gotten around to.
Kevin: So I've just been, I'm not just in bubbly.
Al: Interesting. Well, we'll have more to talk about that later in the episode.
Kevin: Um, things didn't, yeah.
Kevin: Um, yeah.
Kevin: Okay.
Kevin: Uh, what about you?
Al: Obviously, I've also been playing Pocopia and, again, we'll talk about that later. I've also,
Al: however, been playing Tiles Survive. Have you heard of Tiles Survive? So,
Kevin: No, not a word, tell me.
Al: Tiles Survive is one of these mobile games that you always see adverts for and you're like,
Al: What actually is this game?
Al: Finally I caved and I got this game called Tilesurvive.
Al: It looks like it's like a little kind of civilisation building game where you're like adding tiles
Al: and like creating this thing and like building up this little civilisation.
Kevin: Okay. Okay.
Al: And it kind of is but not really.
Al: In so much as like it's very on the rails.
Al: It's like click this button, click this button, click this button and it's like there's not
Al: really game to it.
Al: You keep pressing the buttons and eventually you build up your society and it's like, okay,
Al: great.
Al: That was super fun.
Al: I loved that.
Al: It wasn't super fun.
Al: It was very boring.
Kevin: Is this just Age of Empires?
Al: But like without any actual like control or choice, it's just like this is the civilisation
Al: you're building.
Al: It's very, yeah, yeah, no.
Kevin: What got you to play this?
Al: I just kept seeing adverts for it and I was like, I want to see it because the adverts
Al: looked good.
Al: And it's nothing like the adverts.
Kevin: They always do.
Al: That's the thing.
Al: And I'm like, I don't, I really want to know why these games always put out fake ads.
Al: Like why do they not actually show the game?
Al: Why do they show a different game?
Al: Because the game they show is always better than the game they make.
Al: And so like just make the good game.
Al: If you know what the game, a good game looks like and you know that's what people want
Al: because that's what you put in the adverts.
Al: How about you make the game. I don't know
Kevin: Yeah, that's work.
Al: It's just like constant constant like every letters and numbers and stuff everywhere on the screen
Al: And it's just like you keep pressing buttons to get more number and none of it is fun
Al: And it's like oh, can I unlock this bit of area? No, I must
Al: I must complete chapter four first. Okay, there's almost not and then you go
Al: And then you realize there's a gacha part about getting specific characters and you're like, okay
Al: I see I see what this game is. It's a gacha game
Kevin: Yeah, yeah as it is. I mean that's that's how the mobile games run, but uh, but I don't blame you
Kevin: It's happened to me
Kevin: Um, gosh, what is the one I played it was a slime idol rpg. What was that thing called?
Kevin: Um, it was just the art direction. They got me. Oh
Al: And let me guess, the art was nothing like that in the game.
Kevin: What legend of slime?
Kevin: It was it actually was yeah legend of slime. Yeah, that's what it's called legend of slime. It has a nice little cartoony
Kevin: Thick outline sort of
Kevin: QT look
Kevin: I'll just post this line, but um it was but the gameplay was not good. It was just idle whatever
Al: That's the thing like I'm not against idle games but like don't pretend it's not.
Kevin: But
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: Yeah, I exactly
Al: So yeah I keep seeing other ones and I'm like I'm not gonna follow this twice.
Al: You know I saw one that was like it looked like it was a survival apocalypse type game where you're
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, that's been popping up, where you have the millions of zombies.
Al: like building up a thing and I'm like if it was anything like this advert it would be good but
Al: there's no way it's like this advert because I've seen five different adverts and every single one
Kevin: Nope. That's correct.
Al: one of them looks different.
Al: So anyway, so that's that's that's what I've been up to.
Kevin: There's my Pikachu, I just posted it.
Al: All right, let's get into some news.
Al: First up.
Al: Oh, you're Pikachu.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: Let's have a look.
Kevin: Um.
Al: Ah, Pikachu.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: Happy Pikachu.
Kevin: Um.
Al: All right, let's talk about some news, shall we?
Kevin: All right.
Kevin: Uh.
Kevin: I guess so.
Kevin: Yep.
Kevin: They should have just just gone for the win.
Al: First up, milky delivery.
Al: So this is the funnily enough, the milk delivery game.
Al: This is coming out on the 17th of November.
Al: We finally have a release date.
Al: Well, I mean, actually, the funny thing about this one is, I think this game is going to
Kevin: The 19th.
Kevin: The Cowards.
Kevin: Heh heh heh.
Kevin: At that point.
Al: be short enough that you could probably finish it before the 19th.
Kevin: Yeah, oh, 100% Yeah, yeah. I wonder, I'm just, this is just a separate thought now, but like,
Al: Like this is absolutely it's striking me as like a short hike, like the sort of game you
Al: could get done in a couple hours.
Al: You know, you could probably speed run it to like 15 minutes.
Al: Once you know what you're doing.
Kevin: I don't imagine the Venn diagram between GTA 6 people and cottagecore people is actually that
Al: Look, I refuse to pigeonhole people now. I don't even know, right? I think the GTA circle
Kevin: big. Um.
Al: on that Venn diagram is so big, it must be swallowing up so many other entire circles.
Kevin: is sure for I guess the question.
Al: Like I'm not a big GTA person, and I know that not everyone is, but sometimes it feels
Al: … It's like with, I felt, because we talked a little bit in Discord about the Avatar films,
Kevin: It does. I mean, they have the numbers somehow to back it, right, like it's just.
Al: and I feel that a little bit like Avatar, when it's like, until I actually watched
Al: them last year, I kind of felt like I didn't, it felt like everybody was watching it, but
Al: nobody was watching it, right? Like clearly so many people are watching it. It doesn't
Al: make this much money without so many people watching it, but I don't seem to know anyone
Kevin: Yeah, well, yeah, that's the thing is, well, it's just a couple of things.
Al: who's watched them, other than the first one.
Kevin: One, I think it's for the lack of a better word, the casual person, right?
Kevin: Like your everyday Joe, you know, majority amount of 6 billion humans or whatever.
Kevin: Like people who aren't even quote unquote gamers or hardcore.
Al: Nearly eight. I think you're a little bit out of date with your numbers there.
Kevin: Yeah, I don't know where we're at but you know
Kevin: like
Kevin: Point is like GTA and the avatar films are like beyond
Al: Oh, we're over 8. We're 8.3 now, apparently.
Kevin: Their media. Oh, are we? Oh, okay
Kevin: GT and GTA is still expecting more sales than that. Everyone has to buy it at least three times to me
Al: [Laughter]
Kevin: Anyways, um
Kevin: Like it, you know, it's just it's I think it just somehow catches the attention of the quote-unquote everyday person
Kevin: Who isn't that much into movies or games or you know, heavily invested, but you know, that's that's not just kind of guessing
Kevin: But the question I really have is who in the THS community is down for GTA 6
Kevin: That's what I want to know right that that's what intrigues me
Kevin: Like how big is our vindai specifically cuz you're a cottage core gaming is still big in general
Kevin: but like if you're listening to a
Kevin: podcasts about this niche, you know, genre.
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: And I'll see you next time.
Al: Yeah
Al: 100% gonna buy this game
Al: Next tiny Eden have announced that their release date is the 7th of September
Al: Which is out now as you're listening because that's on the Monday
Kevin: That is oh yeah, it's real yeah for me like I play a lot not just games but a lot of my
Al: This game I'm not probably not gonna play because it just
Al: It looks fine, but it's it's a bit too
Al: Small scale for me. I've played a few games like this and it just ends up being a little bit unsatisfying
Kevin: media consumption is for escapism and fantasyism and so I don't like being reminded I live
Kevin: in a small apartment.
Al: Yeah, yeah, that's a good point. I think that's that's a very good point
Al: I don't like the small scale of it because of that it feels too
Kevin: Yeah, yeah it's too real and not in the graphics just yeah oh I don't like that that's I know
Al: My question is in this trailer the person is cutting up strawberries
Al: But they're not getting rid of the leaves from the strawberries first. They're just cutting straight through the leaves and the strawberry in one go
Al: What are you doing? What are you doing?
Kevin: I don't like that.
Al: Next up Cozy Caravan have announced their 1.6 update Ibis Isles
Al: It is out now. It includes eight new locations on the Ibis Isles.
Al: Ibis Isles is home to a bustling airport, tranquil zen gardens, ancient ruins and more.
Al: There's eight new locations waiting to be explored.
Al: Your island itinerary is going to be jam-packed with 25+ new quests.
Al: Can I just say, see when your number is like under 100?
Al: Don't say plus, just say the number.
Al: [laughs] Right?
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Al: Like if it's over 100, fair enough.
Al: But if it's 27, say 27.
Al: Don't say 25+, that doesn't sound impressive.
Al: [laughing]
Kevin: or just or here's my my version say round it down but don't include the plus so when it's actually over I feel good not you know eh yeah right tell me 25
Al: that is a good way to put it yeah yeah but yeah 25 plus you're like there's no way it's more than 27
Al: right it's not 30 obviously it's not and it's not going to be 28 or 29 because they say almost 30
Kevin: no exactly it's not it's not 30
Al: if it's 28 or 29. There's tons of things to see and do investigate the spooky and maybe slightly
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Al: haunted glowworm caves settle a turf war between the local skaters and surfers save a comedy show
Al: or just enjoy the vacation vibes while relaxing by...
Al: the beach.
Kevin: uh turf war you've caught my interest uh this yeah yeah uh this whole expansion looks pretty
Kevin: sizable to be honest i'm intrigued you caught my eyes uh that was a caravan that's the that's a big
Al: It also unlocks fast travel, this new update, 40+ new food recipes, again with the plus
Kevin: one not 45
Al: there, and new outfits, an undetermined number of new, dozens, sorry, it says dozens of new
Al: outfits, so at least 24, dozens, oh dear, that is out now, so if you'd be
Kevin: Ah, see, there we go, now, now we're, I guess.
Al: playing Cords of Caravan or you've been looking for a reason to, here's another.
Kevin: on sale right now. I don't know if it will be when you're listening, but right now it is.
Kevin: Looks pretty decent. Maybe I'll play.
Al: Next up, something I'm sure Kevin will love. Hammer and Harvest, Dwarven Roots, their kickstarter
Al: is out now, is live now.
Kevin: Let's see here. Um, okay. I do like hammers. I've been known to harvest things
Kevin: I'm just looking here at the video now. Um
Kevin: Nice little pixely 2d thing. Yeah, that's alright. Um
Kevin: Yeah, it's like dwarf. I mean farming. Wow those
Kevin: Portraits are really realistic
Al: The yeah, they're so big as well they cover like half the screen
Al: It's like you are right up in their face. I
Kevin: That's
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, look at all those wrinkles
Al: Forgot I didn't mention that on last week's episode, but when we when we were in there
Al: Was it Codey? I was on when I was talking with Codey. It was like they would I just
Al: Noticed that and like was shocked when I saw that and forgot to mention it afterwards. Yeah, so large
Kevin: Yeah, that's funny. I like it. It has great keepery. Wow. I just get jumpscared every time my portrait pops up.
Al: Now imagine doing it on your TV.
Kevin: I like smithing. I like armoring. Yeah.
Kevin: Yeah, there you go.
Kevin: Yeah, no, this is solid. I like it. You're right. It's caught my attention.
Kevin: I like smithing. I like smithing a lot. I don't know why. It's just something that gets me.
Al: 20 plus days to go on their kickstarter
Kevin: Kickstarter, ain't it?
Al: Uh, it's it's got about a quarter of its way to its goal. Uh, let's see if that continues
Kevin: That's some good luck. That's a bit of a ways to go.
Kevin: Yeah, but it's not.
Al: It is an uphill battle when you've passed the first few days and you're not over half but it can still be done.
Kevin: Yeah, it's only 20k.
Kevin: Yeah, it's only 20k, not a high, high goal.
Kevin: So, all right, good luck Hammer and Harvest.
Kevin: I'll, I'm rooting for you.
Al: Next up, Ova Magica. So they had delayed their console releases because of an issue with the Switch 2
Al: version. They wanted to release all their console
Al: releases at the same time. That had been delayed till the
Al: 8th of September and it has now been delayed further because, not because of the Switch 2 version, but apparently because of the Switch version.
Kevin: Okay, well, well.
Al: Basically, they have they have literally said if we hadn't already promised switch on
Al: the kickstarter, we'd just be giving up on it. I'm just going with switch to. Yeah. In
Kevin: While I commend that, it hasn't stopped a lot of other people.
Al: transparency, had we not promised switch Nintendo switch to backers already, it's very likely
Al: that we would have simply abandoned shipping in on the system in favor of Nintendo switch
Al: to the reason being is that the game is running very smoothly on Nintendo switch to but is
Al: is struggling quite substantially on Nintendo Switch.
Al: the game runs at a smooth fixed FPS without dips, but is currently crashing at certain
Kevin: Oh, good heavens.
Al: intervals due to this issue.
Al: this recently discovered memory leak has been a Herculean task.
Al: have been putting in long hours to ensure the game is in the absolute best form possible.
Al: It hurts a lot for there to be another delay here. We know we are disappointing everyone by
Al: announcing this delay, including ourselves. The reason it's coming so late from us is because
Al: until this week we held out hope we'd be able to get the game stable and passed certification
Al: on Nintendo Switch. However, unfortunately, as we have still not fixed the memory leak issue,
Al: we need to delay once more. We believe very deeply in only shipping a stable game in the best
Al: possible. It's very important to us that we not only fulfill all obligations to backers,
Al: but we also ship the game in the best possible state. They are not announcing a new release
Al: date. It's just coming out at some point, which is the sensible thing to
Kevin: Yeah, look, they knocked us out of the park with their announcement, it's all commendable.
Kevin: Wow, it sounds like absolute hell what they're trying to do.
Kevin: My condolences.
Al: Their only real negative is the fact that they announced a release date before they
Al: knew they could release on it.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: Which is just a standard thing with games now.
Al: My opinion, I've said this time and time again, if you could not release tomorrow, don't announce
Al: a release date.
Al: I just think it is too risky.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, but it's yeah, it's it's tough cuz you gotta know how you know
Kevin: Right. I don't know. I'm not a game dev
Kevin: I do I know but it just you do you still need to a little press beforehand? So
Kevin: That's that stuff. But um, I
Kevin: Know still good for them a good way of tackling it. Um, the only last thing um
Kevin: Let's say is you know, don't feel too bad cuz even Nintendo is not
Kevin: Switch one
Al: Haha, what do you here's a question for you? What do you think about their decision to delay all of the?
Kevin: Um, I guess I would imagine they have those numbers right like I if it were small enough I'd
Kevin: probably go ahead and just drop everything else like the other ones to be honest. I think it is
Kevin: a little weird just for the one kind of uh it's not that Switch like has you know has a major
Kevin: audience but uh I well never mind then uh probably okay then um that would feel extra weird.
Al: They have said that the switch is the vast majority.
Kevin: Never mind that's probably a decent decision in this case.
Al: I just, like, if I was a, you know, not a Switch player and I was an Xbox or a PS5 player,
Al: I'd be quite frustrated with being delayed because of the Switch. You know, because they probably
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I would, maybe, I don't know what you could do,
Al: already don't like the Switch because it's like so underpowered and blah blah blah, not a real
Al: console, blah blah blah, now they're being told they can't get the game because of it. I'd be
Kevin: but I'd release everything else and then maybe a little extra in-game thing for the Switch people.
Kevin: I don't know what, but just a thought. Sorry.
Kevin: We took longer. No, that's it. But, yeah.
Al: Maybe. Just, I don't think there is a good solution to this. I don't think it's completely
Al: wrong for them to do it, but I can see why some people would be very frustrated.
Kevin: Yeah, no, that's fair, but they're trying their best.
Al: This is also maybe why you shouldn't agree to console ports on a Kickstarter when you
Al: don't know for certain how you're going to do that. Just saying.
Kevin: That's rough buddy, um, well, though I should probably try this game at some point the little cow slimes are funny
Al: Yeah, I also should because I think I backed it. I need to check. I did. I did. I did.
Kevin: Sheets, you know, I will commend you al you drop the habit. Yeah
Al: I have it. I have it on Steam. I could go play it now if I wanted.
Kevin: There you go
Al: Do I want? That's the question.
Kevin: We'll see
Al: Just double check it's in my library. It is in my library. Playtime zero minutes.
Kevin: No, there you go
Al: All right. We also have two new games to talk about. The first one is Mayday. After a mysterious
Al: crash, you awaken alone on a strange island. Survive by hunting, farming, and crafting,
Al: then explore a vast archipelago filled with secrets, ancient ruins, and ruins.
Al: Build your base, uncover the truth, and escape if you can.
Kevin: My
Kevin: Okay, a couple thoughts. Well a lot of thoughts. First of all, there's like a giant kraken octopus thing the beginning. That's something
Kevin: The game here, I'm kind of torn because it's
Kevin: No, it's not driving me crazy with the like it's not making too much of an impression the visual style
Kevin: It's 2d stardew esque stuff. Why does the deer look really like detailed and real?
Kevin: It looks like
Kevin: Everything look here looks, you know, nothing to
Kevin: Ending out let's say that um, I could be wrong like I don't know they did something to call their sheep to them
Kevin: That's kind of cool
Kevin: I do think not having you know, assuming they're you know, the premise they're sticking to that. There's not gonna be any other characters
Kevin: That's an interesting call
Kevin: But also having the objective of getting off the island. I think that's kind of neat
Kevin: You know
Kevin: If they really stick into that and there's an end point thing you're fighting a tiger. That's kind of cool. Um
Al: I think that's the most interesting thing to me, right?
Al: 'Cause like, farming game, okay, sure, fine.
Al: Farming, crafting, survival, oh, fine,
Al: whatever, it's been done before.
Al: But with the idea of escaping
Al: and there are no other human characters,
Al: oh, sign me up.
Kevin: Yeah
Al: I don't want no romance. (laughs)
Kevin: There's no romance and it's I mean it's kind of sandboxy
Al: Right?
Kevin: But like this is that's probably the hardest thing for most people who don't like sandbox though an open nature of it, right?
Kevin: Like giving you a goal something to aim for I think that's cool. Um, so yeah
Al: The bosses look interesting the fights look like they could be like all the bosses look really detailed and interesting designs
Kevin: Yep.
Kevin: Yeah, there are.
Kevin: There's robots.
Kevin: There's big animal monsters and cyclops.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: This stuff is going on.
Kevin: There's stuff going on.
Kevin: I wasn't sure at first, but yeah.
Kevin: No, I'm somewhat interested.
Kevin: Escape, that's the thing that's really selling me on it.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: I agree. We'll keep our eye on it. There's a free demo on a release date is coming out on the 2nd of November this year.
Kevin: OK.
Kevin: Mayday survival.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: There's a demo.
Kevin: Free demo.
Kevin: Hm.
Kevin: Isn't that nice when there's a release
Kevin: date and a reasonable time?
Al: Well, assuming it's yes, assuming is not delayed. We will keep an eye on it. And finally, we have Kropia. I'm guessing it's meant to be
Kevin: Not that it can't be delayed, but--
Kevin: Okay, look, look.
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: First, the first thing that has to be said,
Kevin: we all know what we're thinking.
Kevin: And you know, I feel bad
Kevin: 'cause I'm sure they had this lockdown a long time ago,
Al: Well, I'm also thinking like, the name is far too easy to turn into crappie.
Kevin: but anything in opia is done.
Kevin: No, stay away from that.
Kevin: You can't, you can't.
Al: Crappie? I'm more like crappie!
Kevin: That too.
Kevin: [yawns]
Kevin: [laughs]
Kevin: Um, what is this game, Al?
Kevin: We got mining, we got farming.
Al: Cultivate crops, care for animals, fish, mine, resources, and explore diversity.
Al: Environments while growing the local community. Invite village residents to work with you and
Al: collaborate to meet city targets, helping you achieve goals. More if it's Stardew. But 3D.
Kevin: I do think it is started with 3d the
Kevin: The art style is kind of cute. Oh that water animation is not good. Oh, I don't like that
Al: But you do get a moped.
Kevin: You can ride a scooter
Kevin: You do get a moped. Um
Kevin: It's 3d of the characters who kind of like play school with the k brand. Um art style, which is
Al: Yeah, I can't I can't decide on what I feel about the art style
Kevin: Not the worst in the world
Kevin: Yeah, I can't either
Kevin: Um, it, it's stands out, I'll give it.
Kevin: That is it a good sand out? I don't know, but, um.
Al: [laughs]
Al: It stands out, I have something.
Kevin: No, the 1 thing I will give them, like, I do think it's cool is inviting the villagers to work with you because you can see that they're like, helping you farm the water stuff.
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: I don't know how extensive that will be, but.
Kevin: That's that's a good idea.
Al: That is a great way of wording it. It's a good idea, but how often do ideas actually end up
Kevin: Yeah. (laughs)
Al: working well? That's always the question.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, that's the question.
Kevin: Yeah, okay, so keep it, oh gosh, the water,
Kevin: the water looks like a floor.
Kevin: It's not great, it's not great.
Kevin: Gotta start off, that's.
Al: Cropia is out now and there is a demo. There's a demo for
Kevin: Oh, it's out already, oh, oh.
Kevin: Well, you know what?
Al: both of them. Cropia and Mayday both have a demo.
Kevin: Probably need a demo day.
Kevin: I'm intrigued.
Al: Yeah, maybe, maybe. All right, that's the news.
Kevin: What the?
Kevin: [yells]
Al: Shall we talk about Pocopia Bubbly Basin? Kevin, here we go.
Kevin: [laughs]
Kevin: Like you, I have to be restrained from doing so.
Al: Well, let's start off with the free update stuff, shall we? Ease us into it, right? So we've got
Kevin: [laughs]
Kevin: Yes, yes.
Al: diving. Just the diving overall. You can do the diving in the free update. First up, great. We
Kevin: There was so honestly in general. There was so much in the free update a lot of stuff. They didn't tell us about
Al: Yeah, yes, yes. We're not gonna talk about all of the tiny things. I've put the kind of the the main big things there
Kevin: well
Kevin: No
Kevin: Yeah, yeah
Al: I'm gonna be honest Kevin I
Kevin: Yeah
Al: You don't like the diving
Kevin: You don't Wow
Al: No, so right, okay. Okay. Okay. Bear with me. Bear with me. Bear with me
Kevin: Just tell me I won't judge you I'm just curious how
Al: The diving in general is a fun idea and I like it as a concept I
Al: hate that I have.
Al: I have to hold the B button to swim.
Al: Why is there no toggle for that?
Al: You have a toggle for running,
Al: no toggle for swimming.
Kevin: - Well, oh, but that's DLC.
Al: And I hate that.
Kevin: You're right.
Kevin: There's a solution in the paid portion,
Kevin: but in general, that's a good one.
Al: I've not got to that point then yet, so tell me what that is.
Kevin: It's not some, okay.
Kevin: It's not something they, there's,
Kevin: it's not something they tell you actually.
Al: Oh, for goodness sake!
Kevin: Okay, in the DLC, smoothies are introduced.
Al: Yeah, okay, yes, I've not got to that point.
Al: And the reason why I've not got to that point yet
Al: is because I'm just not enjoying the swimming.
Kevin: - Yes.
Al: And so it's, I'm really struggling to get through the deal.
Kevin: - Okay.
Kevin: Okay, well, my, give it a shot.
Kevin: Once you make a smoothie, drink a smoothie,
Kevin: it powers up Surf, and the power up to Surf,
Al: "Boo!"
Kevin: it works underwater.
Kevin: You tap B, you turn into Lapras,
Kevin: and you can just move around.
Al: That is a bad solution to that problem.
Al: Like, I'm not saying that being able to surf underwater is bad.
Kevin: It's not great.
Al: That's fine.
Al: You should still have a toggle.
Al: I think that's an accessibility thing,
Al: 'cause I'm really struggling to hold the B button
Kevin: - Yeah, yeah, well, well, no, I agree.
Al: and also go up and down
Al: and also move the camera at the same time.
Al: It's too much.
Kevin: That's fair, that's fair.
Kevin: Lapras is, becomes a toggle at that point,
Al: Sure, sure.
Kevin: you know, with the limited timer,
Kevin: but it does not solve the key situation of just,
Al: And you know the thing is,
Kevin: it should be a toggle by default, you're right.
Kevin: And it's very strange, 'cause you're right, run has it.
Al: they have an existing toggle for it
Al: because you don't need running underwater.
Al: So you can just use the exact same toggle,
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: which is pressing in of the left stick.
Al: You can just do the same thing.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: They have the solution.
Al: They've done the solution for running.
Al: Why can't you do it for swimming as well?
Al: I almost wonder whether anybody on the development team
Al: ever actually tried doing swimming
Al: for longer than a few seconds
Kevin: I I don't know
Al: before realizing that it's just so not fun.
Al: Too many fingers doing too many things all at once.
Kevin: Well
Kevin: I understand you. Okay. Look I understand the criticism. It's valid. I don't mind it like it just it's fun
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: I don't have much of a problem. It's when you say it when you break describe it. Yes, I think they should have a toggle
Kevin: But here's the kicker like I like
Kevin: Especially everything else like I think it feels good. Um
Kevin: the you know kind of omnidirectional motion
Al: I think that's good. I think that is good. I think that is good. But I just, like, I've not enjoyed it because of that aspect of it, right?
Kevin: Very easy to screw up, right?
Al: Like, the actual swimming up and down, in-game, looks and feels good. It's just that my hand's a cramp trying to do it, you know?
Kevin: Yeah, no, that's that's fair. That's fair. Um, okay. No, that's a fair point. They should add a toggle. And yes, yes.
Al: I have one other complaint. I have one other complaint about swimming.
Al: You can't, like, it's so hard to stay still.
Al: And so, like, we'll talk about this in the DLC about the building and stuff like that,
Al: but, like, it's really hard to, like, do anything underwater unless you're on the ground.
Kevin: Well you have ZL. I mean it's not the perfect solution but you have the button literally to
Kevin: stay in place. Yeah ZL like you know how you know when you're out on the surface
Al: Oh, there is oh, okay. I had not I've not I didn't find
Kevin: in your building and it kind of locks you into snaps you into a grid.
Al: I did not- I didn't realize it did that underwater as well. Okay, good to know.
Kevin: Yes it works underwater and it will just straight up hold you in place so you know
Al: Well.
Kevin: you're not falling or drifting or whatever. Okay well there you go. So give it a shot
Al: Well, now I know.
Al: Okay, I will retract- I will retract that complaint, although I don't know whether
Kevin: with the smoothie and the ZL. Yeah the no the ZL was brief they did mention it but I think it's
Al: I missed them telling me that or whether I was just meant to guess it. I don't know.
Al: Okay, fine, fine. That one's my fault then. That one's my fault.
Kevin: only like one instance so you may have missed it. The smoothie was not made clear because you do the
Kevin: smoothie but they don't actually tell you what it does. You have to try that. Yeah yeah yeah
Al: Yeah, I mean, that's just a problem with their- I mean, their food in general, right? Like,
Al: they're just like, "Oh, here's a- here's a thing." And you're like, "What is this thing?"
Al: And you try it and you're like, "Oh, that's a really cool thing. Maybe you should have
Kevin: Yeah, maybe.
Al: given me more information about that."
Kevin: Yeah, that's fair.
Kevin: I will say this, based just on the nature of this update, there's a good, I think there's a nonzero chance they'll add that toggle in for swimming because I think they are listening to feedback.
Al: Yeah, you're right. I hope so. I hope so. Yeah.
Kevin: Because a lot of this other updates addresses a lot. Well, okay, let's back up. First of all, we get Manaphy.
Al: Yeah, let's, yeah, let's talk about Manaphy. The Manaphy little quest was fun.
Kevin: Right.
Kevin: It's there's a whole new island in bleak beach i'm assuming
Kevin: it was new professor tegrowth said it was new and man if he's there
Al: It was new. I would have noticed that it's definitely new.
Kevin: yeah yeah um which is fun it's your little diving tutorial and it lead in it's fun big
Kevin: funny because man if he literally leaves and says I will leave and see you in the dlc
Al: Yeah.
Kevin: in the paid portion um so yeah
Al: No, it's fun to have, I get like the complaints of DLC and stuff like that, and I get that
Al: this might be frustrating, but I also think it's fun to have like an actual playable teaser
Al: for the DLC, right?
Kevin: It is, yeah.
Al: Like it's, it's not, it's not just like, oh, hey, this thing exists, buy it.
Al: It's like, hey, here's a little taste.
Kevin: Yep.
Al: Here's a little bit of the free stuff.
Al: You get some free stuff here and also get a little taste of what the story might be.
Al: Hey, come and come and buy our DLC that's
Kevin: Yep.
Kevin: It, it is yeah, because yeah the whole diving thing is works really well as exactly as as a teaser.
Kevin: And just opening up you know the water like in bleak beach or if you want to make your own on your cloud island or whatever.
Kevin: But that that little lake in pallet town, you can set up a whole little party down there now.
Al: Yeah. That's, that's a good point. Let's talk, let's talk about the building underwater now
Kevin: Yeah, so diving overall good maybe a couple of spots.
Kevin: Yes.
Al: because obviously that previously, you could technically build underwater, but it would
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: displace the water and you'd end up with weird stuff if you did that. You're welcome. No,
Kevin: We had to be a lunatic to do it.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: it's great. I like it. It works really well. I think they've, they've managed to change
Al: how the physics work enough. That means that it doesn't, you don't feel like you're kind
Al: of hacking it together.
Kevin: It's in fact, it's even better because you don't have to magnify mode to float around and you know
Al: Yeah
Kevin: Build higher or whatever. Oh, that's kind of fun
Al: No, I know about Zio
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: Yeah, I like yeah, it works well works great. Everything works pretty much the same as it does in the surface
Kevin: Yeah, so diving overall good like solid starts to the you know, the free update and introducing you to all that
Kevin: Okay, let's see what else
Kevin: Other lots of little things that they added without telling anyone
Al: Yeah.
Kevin: Flash has now work as trash cans. That's incredible. That was one of the big problems Pocopia had
Al: Imagine that.
Al: Too much stuff.
Kevin: you had
Kevin: Too much stuff and what were your options?
Al: And people are like, "Oh, just throw it on the ground and you'll get rid of it."
Al: And you're like, "Oh, goodness."
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: Just dump it on the dream island to fade into oblivion and but that's a lot of work in itself
Kevin: or just trade, but there's a lot.
Kevin: You need a lot to get rid of it, but whatever this all the they become it's great because every trash can that was already on the world just just updated all of them, you open them there are now a storage thing your place whatever you want to throw away and the next day it will just disappear.
Kevin: Problem solved.
Al: But the best, but the best new item is the portal pod
Al: Which is our finally our centralized storage system
Al: And it feels to me, so I think they've done this really well, in that it feels big enough that it's actually properly useful
Al: Right? You're not gonna be able to store everything in it
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: You're not gonna, you like, you're not gonna store all your like
Kevin: No.
Al: Useless blocks that you might possibly want at some point, right?
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: You're still gonna have to store them somewhere else, but like most items you care about will fit in this
Kevin: At bare minimum, right, you can now set up a crafting station at every location
Kevin: and have access to all the materials on Earth you'd need.
Al: That's that's that's that was gonna be my next point the fact that it still works with crafting stations like the old other storage
Al: perfect
Al: Like I can't
Al: Like this is the difference
Al: I think between like a development team that actually thinks about
Al: The experience of these things and a team that just goes ah you want the feature here you go
Al: Right like I could absolutely see other games
Al: And I'm not naming names because we're not here to do that, but I could absolutely see other games and
Kevin: That's all we were.
Al: implement this.
Al: and then go but it doesn't work with crafting stations and you just be like
Al: no come on what are we doing here right like it's just it's so good
Al: being able to just go to any area and craft and I hate that I didn't have this
Al: when I was playing the game through all the other areas
Kevin: Do you remember how on a certain game you could send items only from certain islands
Kevin: that had no purpose?
Kevin: Not naming names, but I just remember the worst one in my opinion.
Kevin: Anyways, anyways, the portal pod, and the portal pod looks fun, it looks like a little
Kevin: rocket ship almost, and it's like a little teleporter.
Al: - It does, it does.
Al: I'm just glad they gave it a proper name
Al: rather than the transliteral name
Al: that everyone was using before we actually knew the name.
Al: I can't even remember what, oh, I can't remember.
Kevin: What was the, what were they calling it?
Kevin: I don't know.
Al: I can't, give me a minute.
Kevin: Shared storage?
Kevin: I don't know.
Al: I think it was like a shared device or something like that.
Kevin: It's just kind of in the shop
Kevin: along with a number of other little recipes
Kevin: that you can just now buy at the Pokemon Center shops
Kevin: at the PCs.
Kevin: They introduced glass panes
Kevin: and some beams, if I recall correctly,
Kevin: like sort of like calling.
Kevin: I think the glass panes in particular I think were nice because the windows are always constrained to you know kind of like just that with border in the frame and everything, but now you can just do full on glass walls and whatnot, which is perfect you want to build a greenhouse or, you know, terrarium or whatever.
Al: or something underwater. Just, I love making a glass, like in Minecraft I used to build glass
Kevin: Um, yeah, or something underwater.
Al: houses underwater all the time. It's fun. I looked it up, it was shared storage device
Kevin: It's pretty cool. Yeah.
Al: is what people were calling it because that was like the transliterated version
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: from Japanese and I'm like this is a terrible name. Please give it a better name.
Kevin: That'd be that'd be the worst but I wouldn't have trusted them to do better than they did protocol, great names. Oh, yes.
Al: There's loads of these things. One of the little quality of life things that I quite like is,
Al: and it's not something I need to use anymore, but the fact that you can appraise multiple
Al: relics at once now rather than going through them one by one. Oh, beautiful. Love it.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Kevin: It's great.
Kevin: The only kid, well, now it introduced a new problem.
Kevin: Now you need a huge amount of empty space in your pockets for those 50 relics that you
Al: But that's fine because they solved that with the portal pod, why are you carrying stuff
Kevin: have.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Right.
Al: around, you don't need it anymore!
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: You'd have to be a crazy person not to.
Kevin: Or a strong person, some would say.
Kevin: Um...
Al: Any other little quality of life from the free update that you want to talk about?
Kevin: Uh, yeah. Two minor ones with the transformation stuff.
Kevin: Um, the Magnemite, you don't have to confirm to switch every time now.
Al: Oh, I didn't notice that.
Kevin: That was a big one.
Al: That's fantastic.
Al: That's so good.
Kevin: Yeah, I think it's like a toggle, actually. You can just say, "Hey,
Kevin: I don't want to confirm every time" and just switch. Yep.
Al: Good, yeah, that's fine.
Al: Give me all the settings to make my life easier.
Kevin: Yep. Yep.
Al: Absolutely, I'm fine with that.
Kevin: And Graveler can now inhale.
Al: What?
Kevin: I am, I believe so.
Kevin: Actually don't even know if I've done it myself, but Calvin said apparently Graveler can just now inhale, which is incredible.
Al: Oh my word, that's fantastic!
Kevin: Yeah, that's why I said that little issue with the swimming toggle.
Kevin: I think they'll update that because these people care about ridiculous little details like this.
Kevin: Um, yeah, it's it's well, you know, just start a new file.
Al: I'm just annoyed that all this is happening after I've done more.
Kevin: Just do it. No, but yes, it's fine.
Al: No, no, no
Kevin: There's at least one more DLC expansion that you.
Al: I'm really, I know this isn't what we're going to talk about just now, I'm just really intrigued
Al: as to what the second one is going to be, if it's just going to be a bunch of, like,
Kevin: It's snow, it's the snow area.
Al: no, no, that's the third one, because we've got the one at the end of this year that is
Kevin: Oh, oh.
Al: the costumes one, like I'm just really intrigued, is it just going to be costumes, or is there
Kevin: Oh, I don't...
Kevin: Yes.
Al: going to be something else?
Kevin: I don't think it's gonna be an area. I think it's gonna be costumes and maybe other little things.
Al: I know it's not going to be, I don't think it's going to be an area either, but is there
Al: going to be something else?
Kevin: No, I just think it's the drone.
Al: Like I just, what is happening?
Al: It's just such a weird, like, here's a massive new area.
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: Here's a massive new area, and here's costumes.
Kevin: Well, here's the thing though.
Al: Like, is there gonna, like, is there gonna be, like,
Al: even something like, is there gonna be a,
Al: are they gonna put, what are they called,
Al: the things in Gen 4, the showcases,
Kevin: the the the contest pokemon contest.
Al: or what were they called?
Al: Contests, yeah, are they gonna have, like, contests?
Al: Like, we can dress up, and you can do a little contest?
Al: Like, surely there has to be something more than just,
Al: you can put a bow tie on.
Al: Like, it's just such a weird thing to be like,
Kevin: I, yeah, well, if it's for every single Pokémon, that's kind of a lot.
Al: two of three, the second part of three DLCs is clothes.
Al: I'm not saying it's not a lot in terms of like work. I just it doesn't feel like a lot in terms of
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah, well, we'll see. I don't know. I mean,
Al: You know, I know I'm biased against it because like I just generally don't care about clothes and games right but
Kevin: - Yeah, I know that, I mean.
Kevin: That's fair, I just, I don't know,
Kevin: I'm not expecting too much.
Al: Maybe we'll know when this episode comes out.
Kevin: It may be, probably, I will say.
Al: Anyway, sorry for that tangent.
Al: Yes.
Al: Bubbly Basin, the new area, Cerulean City, confirmed.
Kevin: Yeah, all right, let's get to it.
Kevin: Hard, hard confirmed.
Al: Which we know.
Al: Which, I'm just going to put this out there, enjoying that it matched the leak.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, it did, which is good signs
Al: Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Kevin: for other reasons, right?
Kevin: If there was any more information in any of these leaks, you know, who knows what that could mean?
Kevin: Okay, so let's talk about how it starts because it starts in bleak Beach because yeah, of course it's going to
Al: oh oh no minor minor minor minor complaint about how this works. You can come across the um the new
Al: gate and it's like oh you can't come in here yet and then you go and talk to Tangrowth and he says
Al: oh go find this gate. You don't have to do it like assuming you found Manaphy already right? You you
Al: go find the gate and it just says you can't go in it and then you go talk to Tangrowth and he says
Al: go in the gate. There's nothing else there's nothing else you have to do but it makes you
Kevin: Well, yeah
Al: talk to Tangrowth before you can go through the gate but all that talking to Tangrowth is
Al: is telling you to go through the gate. Just let me go through the gate.
Kevin: Yeah yeah I know. Well you have to meet Popplio because he shows you where it is.
Al: I well yeah we can do that we can do that other way it's just such a you you oh it's annoying.
Kevin: Well I mean, how should I put this? It's kind of out of the way. I don't think
Kevin: most people are going to find the gate before talking to Pevers Dinger.
Al: You literally if you're if if right okay so you you swim out to this island
Al: to see Manaphy.
Kevin: Yes. Yes.
Al: And then Manaphy tells you about this new area and you're like oh great I need to go find a gate
Al: and you start swimming south right because that's just where I'm pointing and I come across the
Al: gate I just came across it oh great I found the gate let me talk let me go through it and it's
Kevin: Oh, I didn't think about doing that. Maybe you're right.
Al: like and it's like oh you're not allowed to yet and then so I go talk to Tangrowth and he's like
Al: He's like, "Yeah, go through the gate."
Al: I was like, "I was trying!"
Kevin: I guess so. I guess that's a fair point. I wonder if it spawns if you haven't bought it.
Al: I suspect so and you just it just says that you need to get the DLC to go in there. I suspect
Kevin: I wonder well okay I mean that's a fair point I guess so I didn't think about doing that but
Kevin: yeah maybe more people do find it than I expect yeah yeah you're right you're right okay well
Al: I know it's a stupid little thing complained, but that's what we do here.
Kevin: regardless once you're forced to go talk to this tang growth and they're popular and popular hey
Kevin: come to my home which is somewhere underwater so tang growth cannot come but you first for the
Kevin: game the area that you won't join you I guess other than what is it palatown never mind doesn't
Kevin: in Jorima or Long Island.
Kevin: But kind of story, yes, other than almost half the game.
Al: So other than the two other places where he doesn't come.
Kevin: You follow Poplar through Bleak Beach and there's an underwater town gate you go through and
Kevin: you end up in the Bubbly Basin. I love the Bubbly Basin, like even from, so well first of all,
Kevin: I'm heavily biased towards underwater aesthetics and areas, so I was salivating for this, but
Kevin: not just that, but entering a new area and having all your tools, I was really excited,
Kevin: because I could see, okay, I'm ready to start fixing up everything. But let's see,
Kevin: I mean, it's interesting because there's not much of a story here, to be honest. It's just,
Kevin: hey, here's this town area I live in, it's kind of broken down, can you help me fix it up? And
Kevin: - Okay, well, that's it.
Kevin: - There's no natural disaster, I mean.
Al: There's a very clear natural disaster, Kevin.
Kevin: There's the obvious of, yes, but you can't,
Kevin: unlike the other ones, you're not fixing this one.
Kevin: You're not raising Cerulean City out of the ocean,
Kevin: even though I've thought about this.
Al: Yeah, well, I mean, I don't know if you fix the other ones either. You're learning to live with it.
Kevin: You I mean Kyogre brought rain.
Al: You fix… Okay, Withered Wasteland, I'll accept you fixed that one.
Al: But Bleak Beach, you're not really fixing it.
Kevin: I oh. Right, it was eternal darkness,
Kevin: right? Go clear the sky.
Al: Sure, but you are learning. You don't do that. You're learning to deal with it. You're lighting
Al: up the area. You are learning to deal with that. You're not the one that's actively trying to make
Al: it not like that.
Kevin: Well, I mean you don't okay, you're right you don't aim to do that
Al: Um, whereas in Withered Wasteland your aim is let's make it rain. You're trying to fix that
Al: solution. But in Bleak Beach you're not, in uh Sparkling Skylands you're not, in Rocky
Kevin: Okay, fair enough
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, you're definitely not fixing that either
Al: Roads you're not either. Like I think that that is the norm in this game, is that you're not
Kevin: Okay, you're not fine.
Al: trying to fix it, you're trying to learn to live with it. And if something gets fixed because of it,
Al: okay fine, but you're not actively trying to fix them.
Kevin: Okay.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Okay, fair enough, fair enough. Um, well, regardless, Cerulean City is now underwater completely. Um, well, yes.
Al: [laughter]
Al: Which is fine, 'cause there's no humans to live there anyway, so...
Kevin: Yeah, that's fine.
Kevin: I actually okay the area. It's pretty decently sized area, I guess on par with the other towns.
Kevin: Like, as with everything else, lots of little nooks and crannies to explore. Um, you have this town square. What's interesting about this one. Um, it, how could I put this cerulean city feels like it's been changed, like, if there were no, you know, underwater
Kevin: nonsense cerulean city has changed a little from the let's go area, because there's now this town square area, which was not in the original.
Kevin: That was just interesting to see a little progress in this city, prior to anyone.
Kevin: Anyway, so yeah, you have a town square area, you have a bunch of houses you can find the bike shop, you can find the nugget bridge in the back bills houses out there.
Kevin: Um, really a cave is in there you're at one point you story does take you through it.
Kevin: I think the Cerulean City gym is one of the coolest areas.
Kevin: I'm thinking about excavating it out. I'm crazy, but I'm thinking about excavating.
Kevin: Because you can actually find the, like the roof of the gym, looking out through through some of the sand on top.
Kevin: Um, it was a very big gym. Um, there's this little cafe area near the Pokemon Center once you find it. Um, that's new to cerulean as well.
Kevin: So there's an.
Al: I will say I will say I'm not a fan of where the the fact that the Pokemon Center area is
Al: like so separate to the rest of the area and
Kevin: It is yeah
Al: because it kind of just feels like in most of the areas the the
Al: The kind of where you're doing stuff just kind of like naturally happens around the Pokemon Center
Al: Whereas here it's not it can't really and it's all happening in a different area and like
Al: you're out of the water in the Pokemon Center area, which is fine, but
Al: like I just feel like I'm going out of my way to get to the Pokemon Center and that
Al: just makes everything feel like it moves slightly slower in this area because
Kevin: No, I agree with that because it's kind of out of the way and it's like there's a specific tunnel you have to go through it like you can't just swim to it directly.
Kevin: Yeah, no, I agree because if you work to the pokemon center.
Kevin: It's not yes on the center of town so you have to kind of make your way back to the main area where everything else is.
Al: Well, it's not just that, it's also like the Pokemon Center is the place you go to for a lot of stuff, right?
Kevin: Um, yeah.
Al: Like, doing your challenges and buying stuff and, you know, checking a bunch of stuff.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Al: Like, that's where you do a lot of stuff.
Al: So, I'm just not a fan of it being so out of the way.
Al: I think I might go so far as to say this is my least favorite area in the game.
Kevin: Yeah, no, I agree.
Kevin: Wow.
Al: And that's not to say it's bad, right?
Kevin: Yeah.
Al: Like, I don't think I'm ever going to say anything in this game is bad.
Kevin: Yeah, no, okay, look.
Al: But just that, and also the fact that so much of...
Al: And maybe this is because, maybe I'm just not thinking back to how the other areas felt on first glance.
Al: But it feels like the stuff that I care about, other than the Pokemon Center,
Al: the stuff that I care about in this area is really, really small.
Al: And so, everything else feels quite empty outside of that area.
Kevin: Okay, what do you care about, what do you mean?
Al: Well, like, you know, what you were talking about, all the...
Al: the Cerulean City stuff, it all feels quite close together.
Kevin: Mm-hmm, yeah.
Al: And then the map is still the same sort of size, so most of that map is nothing.
Kevin: That's, hmm, I'm, I think the mind of the kicker, I think it feels like that because you can just swim everywhere.
Kevin: Like, you can literally just like, you know, swim point A to point B. In, let's just say, rock climbing.
Kevin: The Pewter City Museum, you have to find that. Like, there is no clear path until you, you know, did restore that kind of art.
Al: - Sure, but you get to that by the story takes you
Al: into the mines and then you find the mine cart
Al: and you start building out the track
Al: and then you just naturally come to that.
Al: Whereas there's not like a big kind of thing
Al: outside of the main bit of town that you would find.
Al: It's just like a whole bunch of water and sand.
Kevin: Say, okay
Al: And also the fact that that water isn't really that deep
Al: over most of the map.
Kevin: Yeah
Al: you're like kind of like two blocks deep for a lot of it.
Al: and just kind of like floating around and I found the kind of camera angle a bit annoying for that
Kevin: Yeah
Al: because you're kind of like half in the water, half not in the water. I sound like I hate this
Kevin: Mm-hmm
Al: area. I'm not. I don't hate this area. It's just I think it I think it feels lacking compared to
Al: the other ones and maybe maybe I'm being unfair but I...
Kevin: I I kind of I can see that
Kevin: No, no, I I get that feeling a little bit like it's just us the
Kevin: It does feel like the other towns had more stuff that was out of the way or you didn't really
Kevin: Explore it via the story
Kevin: Here the quests trying to take you to all the main areas there's one that will take you through cerulean cave
Kevin: There's one that'll take you down to the very small abyss area
Al: I don't... I don't even hate that. I don't hate... Yeah, the Abyss area, I was very disappointed
Al: with how small that was. No, the... I don't hate that the quests take you to those places.
Al: I think that's fine. I just hate that it's like most of the map doesn't have those areas.
Kevin: Yeah, I think, like, again, I kind of see what you're saying, like, I think part of
Kevin: it is just, it's just so open.
Kevin: You can see everything at a glance.
Kevin: Like there's that little farm area in the corner that I think that's a nice little area,
Kevin: but you can see it at a glance, so I'll just swing by.
Al: Yeah, exactly. But if you think about Withering Wastelands, right, and you think about the
Kevin: Um, yeah, so like there's, yeah.
Al: distance between, say, the Mew cave and the rocket hideout, right, that is quite a large
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Al: percentage of the map. Whereas here, your distance between Cerulean Cave and the gym,
Al: is kind of your farthest part is like maybe a fifth of the map it's like
Al: it's really small. I've not actually looked at it but it feels a lot smaller to me.
Kevin: I don't think it's that small but uh but in general
Kevin: yeah no it does feel smarter
Al: And then Sparkling Skylands like the entire map is something that's interesting and Bleak Beach
Kevin: yeah because it cut up yeah
Al: it's again quite you know think about how far away the SS Anne was when you walked in and you saw it
Al: and then you've got Rocky Ridges is probably the least big in terms of that because you're not
Al: immediate you're seeing.
Kevin: Yeah. Yeah.
Al: a lot of stuff all close together and you have to like actively go in. Maybe there's something I've
Al: missed. Maybe there's the pewter museum equivalent that I've missed. I don't know. Maybe like they
Kevin: >> I don't think so, because I'm thinking.
Al: could like they could have for example had um unless I've missed it somewhere they don't have
Al: like the power plant you could have the power plant somewhere on this at this at the corner
Kevin: Yeah, no they don't.
Al: of you could have that at the corner of the map and that would make it feel so much bigger while
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah, no, like, like I said, or the way I look at it because I understand
Al: not actually including much more.
Kevin: your point and I feel that for, and for clarity like this is actually my favorite area in
Kevin: the game.
Al: [laughs]
Kevin: But I think this is a valid criticism.
Kevin: Because yeah, there's no big areas that are just off, off the, you know, off the beaten
Kevin: path or whatever, like.
Kevin: The biggest is probably the cerulean gym, because you don't really go there for any
Kevin: story stuff. But it's literally like right next to you. You can turn and just see the
Kevin: little entrance right there. But no, I think that's fair. There's no "areas" that are like
Kevin: really hidden or farther away. There's little landmarks like Bill's house. You know, you don't
Kevin: go to Bill's house and it's sizable, but it's not the same as like the...
Kevin: Safari zone in the Withered Wasteland, which I don't think I even saw the Safari
Kevin: zone until after I cleared the Withered Wasteland. I didn't realize it was there.
Kevin: Yeah, no, it's a fair complaint. Like, I still think there's a decent amount of stuff,
Kevin: but you get to see it a lot faster than you would in the other areas. That's 100% true, I think.
Al: Again, I don't, I don't want to, I don't want to get you down.
Kevin: But yeah, yeah. Well, I mean, a big part of it is just ocean, but...
Al: So tell me why you love this area.
Kevin: Because I love the ocean. And yeah, coral popping up. I get to swim everywhere. I like it.
Kevin: It's not specific to this area necessarily, but this is the first one I come in with all
Kevin: the tools, right? So I can start fixing stuff up right away. And I just have a better sense
Kevin: of planning and everything. I think that's fun. I like, you know, as with all the other areas,
Kevin: you think they did a good job?
Kevin: What do you think?
Kevin: The depth is very disappointing as you mentioned, because they kind of had that in the trailer. I was very excited for it. I was imagining the whole thing, kind of diving deep into the depths and it's kind of what it was, but it's just a small area.
Al: Yeah, they show you everything in the trailer for it basically, it's the entire thing.
Kevin: Basically.
Kevin: There's no incentive to build down there, which is kind of a shame.
Al: No I also find it's a little bit of a weird thing where if you're kind of like hovering
Al: near the entrance you can kind of switch between the two and it gets a bit bugged out and it
Al: can't, you can't, it doesn't know whether you're, you can be like in the upper area
Al: but it thinks you're in the lower area and it just ends up with some weird bugs.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, it does. It's pretty funny. Yeah. Yeah. Um.
Al: It feels like they had a great idea for this but didn't end up actually putting much into it
Kevin: Okay, I.
Al: and they're like "oh sure, throw that in."
Kevin: I don't know, because I think everything's in there is well done. Like, I think felt just thoughtlessly.
Kevin: Lost in there, I just think it needed more if anything right? Like you said, the power plant, if they had that somewhere, I think that would be great.
Kevin: Um...
Al: Yeah, the power plant could have been down in the depths, right?
Kevin: But yeah, yeah, oh yeah, that would have been awesome.
Kevin: Um, now, oh man, I want that so bad now, um, but, uh, c'est la vie.
Kevin: Um, okay, let's, I mean, that's the area, kind of, in general. Let's talk about, um,
Kevin: again, the quest line, like, it's, I don't know, like, again, like you said, in the other areas,
Kevin: is maybe you're not solving the problem.
Kevin: But there's very like specific objectives right like even in Rocky Ridge, it's they want to build a party whatever but like you're working towards it they said that they lay that out.
Al: I, yeah, there's not a big overall thing. It's more like, here are five features that we've
Al: added into the game in this area. Here are the five quests that you do to unlock those and explain
Al: them to you. And it's like, sure, that's fine and that works well and that's a good way to explain
Kevin: Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Al: these things to you, but like, there's nothing more than that. There's not like an all-encompassing
Al: for it. As you say, everything in Rocky Ridges is here's a new thing for you and that's great,
Al: but you're doing it all to get the party, right? Everything you do in that area is to get the
Kevin: - Get it to rain.
Al: party. And again, Withered Wasteland, everything you do, they're adding a whole bunch of things,
Al: but everything you do is to get it to rain. And again, with Bleak Beach, it's like, yeah,
Al: there's lots of little things they give you here, lots of little extra things, but everything is to
Kevin: Yeah. Light up the town.
Al: to make it light.
Al: And then with Sparklings.
Al: It's all about building up the thingy.
Kevin: Building the skyscraper. Yeah.
Al: And here it's like, oh yeah, you've got all these things, but not the big overarching
Al: thing and that's the reason why.
Kevin: Nope. Nope. Which is probably, which is, again, disappointing a bit to me.
Kevin: Because again, all the little side quests are fun and nice and you interact with a few Pokemon,
Kevin: but I'm not, other than just fixing up the town in general, like there's no overarching,
Kevin: Yeah, like, "Float."
Kevin: They don't have the little meter.
Al: - Yeah, I don't even think there's a specific order
Kevin: No, no.
Al: that you have to do these in either.
Al: Like it's just, they just appear when they appear.
Kevin: The, you know, aside from the last one, um, uh, yeah, but, uh, oh, okay.
Al: Sure, which I've not got to yet, that's fine.
Kevin: Um, well, anyways, um, but the, that said, again, all the quests they do have are enjoyable.
Kevin: Like, I like the crew, you meet Popplio, you meet, um, some of those early Pokémon like Forcelote.
Kevin: Popplio has the one to teach you about farming underwater, which, uh, was interesting because there's a little extra step.
Kevin: I mean, it's just like your other ones where you, you know, you get to prepare the ground and plant your seeds or whatever.
Kevin: But you also have to kind of provide bubbles, provide air for the, uh, the farm, the crops underwater.
Kevin: And you just do that with, like, the water Pokémon that has the bubbling feature.
Kevin: Um, they introduced watermelons in this up in the DLC, which is...
Kevin: ...fun because you need an extra step after you harvest them.
Kevin: You need to bring it to someone who can cut them.
Kevin: Um, uh, which, uh, which, uh, yeah, okay, that makes sense for a watermelon.
Kevin: Um, yeah, uh, the quest is kind of cute because I can't remember.
Kevin: It's Mudkip, I think, who wants the watermelon.
Kevin: Or is it Corsola? I don't know, regardless.
Kevin: One of them, um, and they're trying to eat the watermelon, but it's all nasty tasting because they're just eating the skin or whatever.
Kevin: And then that's when you.
Kevin: Think of, oh, hey, let's find somebody who can help cut this open. So, you harvest watermelon, just slice them up and get watermelon slices.
Kevin: Um, yeah, so I think that that was a fun little way to do the farming and I really like watermelon in general. So.
Kevin: More more points were probably beats and, um, let me think what what else? Um.
Al: One thing, because I've also not done the farming underwater, one question I have is can you still do automated watering underwater?
Al: Because I know you have to water them despite being underwater, but can you, do the sprinklers work?
Kevin: I haven't tried, but I'm assuming yes, I don't see why, why there wouldn't be a reason not to. Well, because yeah.
Al: Well just because you're, it's, it's, it's, you're underwater, right? And so like the water itself isn't doing it.
Kevin: Yeah, well, no, I, I think you do. Do you have to water? I don't think you have to water.
Al: So maybe the sprinkler wouldn't either.
Al: Think you have I think I think you have to
Kevin: I think you just have to provide the air sort of thing which there's no automation for that actually.
Al: get the Pokemon to manually water.
Kevin: I have to look into this. I haven't done too much of the farming. There is the one field and you got a lot of watermelons from it, so I haven't done it too much.
Kevin: I'll have to dig. I'm curious. I don't know. That's a good question. That's a problem.
Kevin: But you can just take your watermelons to your other farms, which I know it's just circumventing the problem.
Kevin: But no, that's a fair criticism. I think about it. I don't know if there's a way to auto air the farmer water or whatever.
Kevin: Yeah, I'll have to look into that.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah. I'll report back. I'll look into this because it's a good question.
Kevin: Okay, so let's see. What are the quests? There's the smoothie quest. Mudkip wants to make smoothies.
Kevin: And so you help it find the blender. And like I said, the power up surf.
Kevin: You move pretty dang fast with surf underwater. I'll say that, which is kind of fun.
Kevin: Well, let's see. There's Popplio. There's quests to find several Popplio's friends, which takes you to the different areas of the map and explore.
Kevin: It's just a couple simple quests. Totodile is fun because you have to play a few games with Totodile because Totodile loves to play games.
Kevin: But the other ones. Oh, one of the new little materials is pearls.
Kevin: Let's talk about that because you harvest pearls lying around, kind of like mushrooms.
Kevin: But then you have to clean them up because they're always kind of grubby and dirty.
Kevin: And so you have to meet certain Pokemon to help you clean.
Kevin: One little interesting thing this is the first time I think I saw it in the side quest, where they actually give you options for when you do the quest, they give you a habitat to spawn a Pokemon but you can get the different habitats.
Kevin: For instance, I got a habitat for Cloyster to, to spawn in Cloyster will clean the pearls because of course Cloyster, my brother Calvin got the habitat for Sharpedo will clean it up with stress.
Al: Yeah, I saw Sharpedo was one of them
Kevin: So that was kind of neat and interesting.
Al: Cool
Kevin: Um, just, just mix it up a little. Um, let's see what else. Oh, floating.
Al: One that one that you can do is actually onyx, but I wouldn't recommend taking onyx to
Al: Bubbly Basin
Kevin: So that's one thing I haven't tried. And I want to see but I wonder how that teleporting works for different Pokemon.
Al: Yeah, I don't know I don't know
Kevin: I don't know, I haven't tried it. I've played all this and have not tried it, which is a shame.
Al: Is that annoying when you just think of something live on the podcast you're like, oh, why haven't I done that?
Kevin: Yeah, well, that just means a follow-up, that's all it means.
Kevin: But there's a quest to build a house and because...
Al: Oh, you can so you can create air pocket areas
Kevin: You can. And that goes with the house actually, because the house is a submarine. It's a
Al: And that's where that's where they have to go
Kevin: building kit and you can place it anywhere because we now have floating blocks and they can serve as
Kevin: a base to build whatever, wherever. I love the submarine kit because it's actually the
Kevin: Team Aqua submarine from Alpha Sapphire. And so you build it and you can put it
Kevin: literally wherever you want. I put mine near Nugget Bridge. And yeah, so there's a little
Kevin: air pocket. If I did bring a Pokemon, it will warp in there, I'm sure, but I'm just curious.
Kevin: I assume, say, Magikarp. I'm sure I could spawn Magikarp there and just bring it wherever you
Kevin: want in Bubbly Basin.
Al: Yeah, there are a lot of Pokemon that you can just take, but some apparently won't.
Kevin: But yeah, I'm sure I'm gonna explore a little bit I'm curious about, like, can I bring Greninja I don't know. We'll see. Um, and, you know, that's partially I think why maybe Pokemon the Pokemon Center is not underwater.
Kevin: Before you build a house because you'll work there.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Um, but a grant again still didn't solve the problem of being kind of foreign separate. Um, but, but yeah.
Kevin: It's fun set of questions. Again, just just like the rest of Pocopia go around building stuff meeting new Pokemon.
Kevin: And let's talk about some of those Pokemon.
Kevin: It's almost all water exclusively.
Kevin: There was Inkay and Malamar water. That's like the only ones I can think of everyone else's water Pokemon. Um, did you have any favorites that you saw respond.
Al: I mean, Cursola is a fun one. I'm a little bit sad that they didn't do anything with
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: I'd love Corsola.
Al: Cursola.
Kevin: Yeah, or Marini. Oh, no.
Kevin: Yeah, there's furniture, there's a Corsola Light,
Kevin: but they didn't have the Galerian or the other one.
Kevin: Yeah, and then it actually spawned, which is disappointing.
Kevin: Also, they don't acknowledge how Marini wants to eat and kill Corsola.
Al: Well, to be fair, just because you haven't experienced some, what's the word, speaking,
Al: just because you haven't experienced some dialogue about that doesn't mean there's not
Kevin: That's a good point. It could be I may not have just seen that conversation. You're right.
Kevin: Um, what that does feel like something they would address they they dressed mega evolution
Kevin: in this one. Um, so I would be surprised. You're right. I probably just missing it.
Kevin: Um, yeah, a lot of Pokemon a lot of fun stuff popular line is great. The total downline
Kevin: very fun. Um, Golisopod and wind potter great ones. Um, Starmie is perhaps
Kevin: one of the coolest spawns in the entire game. Um, because it's it's a actually put this
Kevin: it's a quest that's not acknowledged as a quest. Um, because one of the things that
Kevin: you can find in bubbly basin, their treasure maps buried there in the glowing blocks that
Kevin: you punch, you can find treasure maps. And if you follow those treasure maps using the
Kevin: dowsing machine and the Pokemon search, you will find pokeball replicas kind of like the
Kevin: the ones they actually sell, they look like that.
Kevin: And so, to spawn Starmie, you have to have like a set of pedestals with all the Pokeball replicas.
Kevin: And it's kind of set up right in Cerulean Gym for you to do so.
Al: Yeah, I've seen that because I got the habitat, but I've not got any of the pokeballs yet.
Al: But yeah, it looks like a fun game.
Kevin: Yeah, it's a fun-- yeah, little side quests to do and hidden side quests and little areas to find are kind of fun.
Kevin: Because they're all pretty much hidden rooms that you wouldn't find that easily otherwise.
Kevin: But yeah, no, that's good stuff. Bubbly Basin. Anything else you want to discuss or ask, Kyle?
Al: I think, so, I've said a lot of negative stuff,
Al: but I do think this is overall fun.
Al: It's good.
Al: I think they could have done better,
Al: but I think it's still good.
Al: I think, personally, what I'm probably going to do
Al: is finish it later.
Al: I think I might kind of try and bundle together
Al: the DLCs to play.
Al: I mean, if the second one does end up
Al: just being the costumes,
Al: then I might not even be on that episode.
Al: We'll see.
Al: I'll at least boot it up
Al: and see what's happening for that one.
Al: But certainly, one in three, I suspect,
Al: I'll probably try and finish them at the same time.
Al: I think part of my problem is,
Al: I finished everything else before this, right?
Al: So there's nothing else I can do other than Bubbly Basin.
Al: [laughs]
Al: And so I'm kind of just like,
Al: oh, kind of drudging through some of the stuff
Al: that I'm not finding as particularly fun
Al: because I'm not enjoying the movement as much.
Al: And so maybe when I have the other area as well,
Al: it might be more fun to kind of mix and match
Al: between them a little bit.
Al: But--
Al: I don't want people to think I don't like this.
Al: I think it is good, it's creative, it's fun.
Al: You know, the Pokemon continue to be the best part of it
Al: with your conversations with them and stuff like that.
Al: And they do do a good job of like telling,
Al: showing you most stuff through the quests,
Al: which is what Pokopia's strength has always been
Al: is it shows you a lot through the quests,
Al: but then has hidden stuff that you,
Al: doesn't matter as much, but you can find and that's fun.
Al: There's been some of that as well,
Al: but I just feel like there's something missing
Al: for that overall kind of gelling it all together.
Kevin: Yeah, no, that's fair. As someone who does love this area, probably my favorite area so far, I can see, I see that. It would be nice to have a power plant in somewhere.
Kevin: Just a little something to round it out a little more.
Al: I mean, I suspect they didn't do the power plant because of the, you know, the Pallet
Al: Town version of it, but yeah, but you could still do it because it's in ruins.
Al: You still need to build the other one to get Zapdos to come back, right?
Kevin: Exactly. Man, that would be so cool. Like you said, what if it were in the abyss and you light it and you get it working again to light it up, that would be so cool.
Kevin: Um, but c'est la vie. Oh, yeah. Okay.
Al: What about you, what's your overall thoughts on it then, before we finish up?
Kevin: Yeah, I mean, I love it.
Kevin: Here, do we need to ask me I love it. It's great didn't disappoint me at all.
Kevin: I'm almost having all the tools and just being able to rebuild stuff as soon as you get the recipes like it was really good.
Al: Yes, yeah.
Kevin: I, within a week. I was able to get like almost the entire pokedex, just because it was just that easy to make stuff and spawn, which is, which is pretty fun.
Kevin: Yeah, no thumbs up all around good stuff.
Al: Yeah. Cool. Yeah, that's fine. All right. Well, thank you very much for joining me to talk about
Kevin: I don't think anything specifics but I think I've covered it all.
Al: Pokopio once again. Is there anything you would like to share with,
Kevin: Thank you, Al, for having me on.
Kevin: Thanks for letting me out of the cage.
Kevin: [laughs]
Al: is there anything you would like to share with the audience?
Kevin: Uh, no, I...
Kevin: Well, I mean,
Kevin: we'll jump to it, but I'll be posting stuff on Slack
Kevin: from Worlds. Look forward to that
Kevin: greenhouse. That's a worthy one, for sure.
Kevin: Other than that,
Kevin: whatever.
Kevin: Get hyped. It's really funny,
Kevin: the next... I feel like they'll tease
Kevin: the third DLC
Kevin: on that Nintendo Direct, but we'll see.
Kevin: Anyways, yeah, I'm good for prayers were
Kevin: but it's fine. I'm back on Instagram. I'm not posting stuff yet, but when I do, we'll let you know. Um, right now, go ahead.
Al: You can find the podcast on Tumblr and on BlueSky at THSPod.
Al: We're also posting clips of the podcast
Al: on YouTube and BlueSky.
Al: We just had one yesterday get, what is it?
Al: 200 views.
Kevin: Wow, look at that!
Al: Which is more than I normally get in a month.
Al: So, we're getting somewhere maybe.
Al: You can also send us feedback from our website,
Al: and tell us what your favorite Pokemon
Al: from the Bubbly Basin is.
Al: And if you don't have Bubbly Basin,
Al: tell us why you're sad about not having it.
Kevin: Tell us about GTA 6.
Al: [laughs]
Al: Tell us about why we missed the news that's happened
Al: after we recorded, but before we released.
Kevin: There you go.
Al: You can also find links to everything
Al: to do with the podcast on that website,
Al: including a link to our Patreon, patreon.com/thspod,
Al: where we will have some Greenhouse episodes coming up soon.
Al: We're also, it is September now.
Al: So we are going to start thinking about the end of the year. So if you think that there's a game
Al: that we need to consider for the game of the year that we haven't talked about on the podcast,
Al: tell us. Because this is the time of the year where I panic and go, "Oh no, there's so many
Al: games I've not played. How am I meant to do a good job of deciding game of the year
Al: when I've not played all of the games yet?" So tell me what you think I should.
Kevin: That's the thing, Al, I think we've established we do not do a good job at this.
Kevin: It's the expectation.
Al: But yet we still have a two and a half hour long episode about it every year
Kevin: We missed wildflowers and that's going to haunt me forever.
Al: All right, I think that's everything then
Al: Kevin thank you for joining me again
Kevin: Thank you, Al.
Al: Listeners, thank you for listening and until next time have a good underwater harvest
Kevin: Good horse.
Kevin: There you underwater husband.
Theme Tune: The Harvest Season is created by Al McKinley, with support from our Patrons including our
Kevin: That's trying to make a joke.
Kevin: You beat me to it.
Theme Tune: Pro Farmers Kevin, Stuart and Elisa, our art is done by Micah the Brave and our music is
Theme Tune: done by Nick Burgess. Feel free to visit our website HarvestSeason.club for show notes
Theme Tune: and links to things we discussed in this episode.
Kevin: Bubble those watermelons.